I've long believed that Epstein was uh
what's called an access agent of the
Israeli Mossad. It it makes zero sense
that he would have anything to do with
the CIA. The CIA is not interested in
this kind of thing. He has no access to
foreign classified information. You're
the leader of the Mossad and you want to
know what American former presidents are
saying, what British royal family
members are saying, what the richest men
in the world are saying. You're not
going to recruit them, right? You
recruit a guy who does have access to
them and over massages being given by 15
and 16 year old girls and plenty of
alcohol, maybe a little coke. The reason
we haven't seen it laid out for the
American people to see is that very
heavy hitters of both major political
parties are involved.
>> And welcome to another episode on TMJ's
political current podcast. When people
hear the CIA, they often think covert
operations, classified files, secret
missions, and everything we see go down
in Hollywood movies. But CIA
whistleblower John Kuryaku, who I have
on today, says the real power isn't in
what governments do, but what they
convince people like you and I to
believe. Because from Iran and Syria to
Venezuela and Iraq, US intelligence has
helped shape war narratives, regime
change operations, and decades of
policy. All while the media often
focuses on a completely irrelevant set
of details and misses the bigger
picture. So today with John, we're not
just going to rehash the same headlines.
We're going to discuss how exactly those
narratives are built from the inside,
who they benefit, and why the truth, the
real truth, never really makes it out.
John obviously needs no introduction. He
has definitely paid the price for what
he has said as a whistleblower. And so,
you definitely don't want to miss this
conversation.
John, thank you so much for joining us
on TMJ News. It's wonderful to have you
on. And today, I want to actually cover
lots of topics. I'm going to start off
with the Epstein files. We're going to
get into America and Israel, as well as
America's foreign policy in the Middle
East. But before I get into all that
good stuff, all the complicated, you
know, conversations, I want to actually
start off on a personal note. something
that I know for many of us on this side,
the perception that we have about the
CIA and what it really means is really
shaped only by what we see from movies,
from you know, Hollywood movies, this
perception that it's all about secrets
and secret operations. Um, but I know
you've said previously that the real
power here is in shaping what people
think they know. Can you tell us what's
really part of that CIA influence, the
CIA deception, if you will, that the
public most misunderstands?
>> Wow, that's a tough question. That's a
tough question because it's I think it's
different for for each person. And it's
different for each group of people in
that I I'll tell you the one thing that
bothers me the most that angers me the
most is I'll go on a podcast or it
doesn't have to be me. can be any it
could be Ray McGovern, Ed Snowden, it
could be anybody. And there is always
one in the comment section
who writes, "Once CIA, always CIA." Like
they have some epiphany or something,
>> right? That is the most intellectually
lazy,
stupid,
thoughtless position that anybody could
take, especially when talking about a
whistleblower. And I'm not talking about
just myself. I'm talking about, like I
said, Ray McGovern, Ed Snowden,
I could Josh Schulty, I could name a
half a dozen other people. Um, so
there's this idea that once you're in
the CIA that you're somehow never
allowed to leave.
Where did that come from? What did they
base that on? There are a lot of very
stupid people out there. There are a lot
of very easily manipulated people out
there. The CIA knows that and takes
advantage of it because it causes splits
in the anti-CIA
populace.
So the CIA will will do a lot of
different things uh to to capitalize on
on that
stupidity that is so common out there.
Uh they will work with Hollywood to make
sure that everything that comes out of
Hollywood is pro-CIA.
They will make themselves look like
Supermen, like they are everywhere.
They're in every aspect of our lives and
there's nothing we can do about it.
That's true. And I I'm sorry. It's true
that they that they try to do it. It's
not true that they're everywhere.
They're omnisient. They're omnipotent.
Quite the opposite is true. It's that if
you look at literally every major global
development
since the CIA was founded in 1947,
it's either gotten it wrong analytically
or it's missed it alto together. And I
mean everything from the B Berlin wall
being built
to 911 and the the Russian invasion of
uh Ukraine and everything in between.
They've just gotten literally everything
wrong.
So I think that's probably the the big
one. They know that a lot of people are
just plain stupid. They know that people
are easily manipulated.
And so they set out to manipulate them.
>> Right. And and you're mentioning
obviously that this perception exists
among the public that the CIA and
oftentimes in in global discourse when
it comes to this CIA and MSAD are often
mentioned together that you know
organizations like the CIA and MSAD are
untouchable. They you know as you just
mentioned have influence on pretty much
every aspect of your life. I heard, you
know, there was a clip that many people
started sharing recently that, you know,
the CIA even can influence, you know,
turning on and off your TV at home and
listening to your conversations and
stuff like that. So,
>> is that perception true or is it is it
not?
>> Oh, no. They very much can do that. Th
this was all laid out. It's funny to me
that this clip that you're talking about
has taken on a second life because that
information was released in 2017 by Josh
Schulty. Um, well, Josh Schulty sent it
to Wikileaks and Wikileaks released it.
It was part of what's called the Vault 7
revelations.
Uh, so yeah, it's very much true that
the CIA can can turn on your smart TV
without it looking like it's on. They
can turn the speaker into a microphone
and they can listen to everything that
goes on in that room. All the while you
are thinking that the TV is off.
>> Interesting. I mean, that's that's
that's quite horrific to be honest with
you, especially for Americans who, you
know, and this conversation becomes
sensitive for people I know who are
particularly vocal online about their
political views. That's often something
they're scared about is, you know, I am,
you know, going to be either stopped at
the airport or have everything checked
or, you know, the CI there's like a
there's a running joke that's like, you
know, your special designated CIA agent
just like watching every move you do.
So, that's definitely a perception
that's there. But I guess the reason
why, you know, I asked this question
from you is as someone who's been there,
it seems to me almost as though there's
lots of misunderstandings people do
have. But um the the bigger question
here that I want to get into is the
Epstein situation. And the reason I want
to start with that is not just because
it's something people are are talking
about and there's lots of misconceptions
about it, but also because we know that
when there's cases that involve
high-profile people or global figures,
as you mentioned, the CIA is generally
involved because, hey, these are, you
know, these are top shots. So why do you
think then with this case in specific
with the Epstein situation, there was
such a lack of institutional curiosity
about it for so long?
I really believe that there
that there was I wouldn't call it a lack
of institutional curiosity so much as I
would call it
the deep state's
efforts to squaltch it. I've long
believed that Epstein was uh what's
called an access agent of the Israeli
MSAD. Um, people point it makes zero
sense that he would have anything to do
with the CIA. The CIA is not interested
in this kind of thing. He has no access
to foreign classified information.
There's no way. There hasn't even been
any credible accusations that he was
involved with the CIA. The FBI, however,
is different. But even that makes far
less sense than the Israelis.
What an access agent is is, let's say
you're a foreign intelligence service.
Let's say you're you're the Mossad.
You're the leader of the Mossad and you
want to know what American former
presidents are saying, what British
royal family members are saying, what
the richest men in the world are saying
about some issue or some person or some
idea or whatever. You're not going to
recruit them, right? You're not going to
be able to say, "Hey, I'll give you
$1,000 a month if you report to me in a
hotel room in Cairo every month." That's
not going to happen. So, you do the next
best thing. You recruit a guy who does
have access to them and over massages
being given by 15 and 16 year old girls
and plenty of alcohol, maybe a little
coke, you get those answers and you pass
it back to the Mossad which may or may
not ever use it for something. Maybe
there's a blackmail in uh operation
underway. Maybe there's not. Maybe
they're just putting it in file. So, I
think that's what we've seen here. The
reason why we haven't seen it go viral,
the reason we haven't seen it laid out
for the American people to see is that
very heavy hitters of both major
political parties are involved. You
know, you've got both Donald Trump and
Bill Clinton. You have uh Prince Andrew
and Bill Gates.
I who isn't involved? you know, Alan
Dersowitz is there getting massages and
half of the the most important insiders
in American politics and economics. And
I think that because they're very
powerful and they're very wealthy and
they have friends in very high places,
they've been able to keep this as quiet
as possible.
>> 100%. And and I know you also touched
upon how agencies often times tend to
protect institutions
>> um rather than than justice. Do you see
evidence of that in this situation? What
essentially what do you think is really
being protected here and why is it being
protected to this degree?
>> Honestly, I think the FBI is being
protected because the FBI has an
enormous division called the counter
intelligence division. The job of every
single person in the counter
intelligence division is to find spies
on American soil and to root out moles
that may have been placed inside the
American government.
But we've always had this hands-off
attitude toward the Israelis. We all
know the Israelis are spying on us. They
have hundreds of spies arrayed across
America, mostly stealing defense
secrets.
So why hasn't the FBI gone gone after
them? And assuming that Epstein was an
Israeli operation,
that would account for the fact that
they've tried to keep this quiet because
they would have to protect the FBI from
people like you or me accusing the FBI
of being asleep at the switch. I think
that's what it is.
>> So would you say that's the bigger story
then? Because one, you know, one thing
we also know is the media at least often
times tends to fixate on all the wrong
details when it comes to this stuff. And
and I know it's a different situation,
but I often think about, you know, Iraq
and the weapons of mass destruction
narrative that was kind of really
hammered in the media going after, you
know, very
>> specific details of like what were these
weapons? You know, what were these? And
then later on it comes out, okay, that
wasn't even the right detail to focus
on. There were no WMDs. And now the
question becomes, so the bigger question
that the media at least was missing was
how come this was even happening? Why
was the justification for war being made
and what was the purpose of it? So, it's
this example of we're missing that
bigger story. Would you say Israel is
that bigger story in this situation?
>> I would. I've been speaking out over the
last 6 to 12 months, I guess, about um
the fact that the Israelis spy on the
United States. And I've been speaking
out in favor of Palestinian human
rights. there's a terrorist attack
against you. Okay, people don't want to
see terrorist attacks against anybody,
but you can't have as your policy to go
in and kill everybody or to push out
everybody and kill women and children
and elderly and sick people and blow up
hospitals and ignore human rights and
murder UN workers and murder
journalists. That can't be the policy.
So, I've been accused of being
a noted anti-semite.
I saw that two weeks ago. I actually I
actually laughed out loud when I saw it.
I'm a noted anti-semite. And then in um
in a comment um actually it was on that
viral clip that you're talking about,
somebody called me very sli simply, flat
out a Jew hater.
Well,
no. Number one. Number two, I'm going to
work against anybody
who is spying on my country. Anybody.
Now, there was a case in the 1980s
where a Greek American by the name of
Steven Lis was spying for the Greek
government. Steven Lis deserved to die
in prison. He didn't. He was released.
He moved to Greece. He became a Greek
citizen. He's a big hero over there. But
anybody spying against the the United
States deserves the worst that the
judicial system can throw at him. And
the Israelis are spying on the United
States.
>> And on the topic of, you know, spying in
intelligence, I think this is also
something no one can really even answer.
And it's this longstanding belief that
US intelligence
can't fully disentangle its priorities
from Israel's,
>> right?
>> Um, from your experience,
>> is there a structural dependency that's
built into this relationship? Is there
something bigger here? Something deeper?
>> Yes. Yes. And it started in 1969 when
Richard Nixon said that um the US would
protect Israel under any circumstances.
Our foreign policy changed in 1969 to
guarantee Israel's safety and security.
That was also about the same time that
Apac became a major force in American
politics. Apac has been around since the
50s and from the 50s to 1969, 197071
it would make, you know, campaign
donations to this candidate or that
candidate and, you know, would put out
position papers, whatever, just like
every other lobbying group. But now it's
it's like a country in and of itself.
And if you don't tow the line, the
Israeli line in Washington on Capitol
Hill, they will primary you and they
will spend millions of dollars to defeat
you and they're very successful.
Well, that might be great for Israel,
but I'm not an Israeli citizen. I want
what's great for America
and uh this system that we have now it's
just not working out. Also, and I don't
mean this rhetorically, I mean it
literally. Why does Apac not have to
register as a foreign agent? It's it's a
mystery to me and literally no one has
ever offered up a believable reason.
It's because they get special treatment
at APAC.
And you know, one other reality that we
know has taken place, we know
intelligence professionals, you know,
like yourself, they often have insights
that rarely make it to into public
discourse. I know for you, many have
benefited actually from your experience
and explaining all of that. But based on
your time in the government,
>> what would you say the average American
completely misunderstands about Israel's
political influence in in Washington?
I think I think the thing that most
people
don't understand and I mean including
friends and family members of mine um is
that
often times American foreign policy and
Israeli foreign policy do not coincide.
And
you know there's a there's kind of a
famous saying in diplomacy. It's there's
no such thing as permanent friends, only
permanent interests, right? And if we
have national interests that coincide
with the Israelis, God bless. But if we
have interests that diverge from the
Israelis, we need to do what is best for
the United States and let the Israelis
do what's best for Israel.
Now, like I say, often times that means
we cooperate with the Israelis. Good.
But much of the time we shouldn't be
cooperating with the Israelis because we
don't have the same national interests.
>> And another, you know, aspect to this as
well is the media. So I know, you know,
these are average Americans often times
misunderstanding, you know, that that
relationship that you just described,
but we've also had situations, and I
think you've also discussed this before,
how intelligence agencies will sometimes
plant stories in the media
>> and um especially when it comes to
obviously we know Israel and its
operations. We know that in, you know,
mainstream media in the US at least, it
often appears without scrutiny. It's
almost as if it's not even a question um
that it appears in this way. What are
some ways that you've seen how Israeli
intelligence shapes American media
narratives, especially on this issue?
>> Oh my gosh, just look at the we we would
need two hours just to talk about this.
Just look at the 9/11 attacks and the
story of the dancing Israelis.
A lot of people think that that is just
some anti-semitic trope that somebody
made up. No. There were Israeli
intelligence officers in New York in the
weeks before 9/11 who were indeed
arrested taking pictures of the World
Trade Center and then dancing after it
was hit. Um when they were picked up by
the NYPD, they were told, "No, no, no.
We're the good guys. It's the Muslims
that did this. We're the good guys. Why
are you taking pictures all week long of
the World Trade Center and then just
standing there waiting for planes to hit
it and then you you're dancing in the
streets. So, in the end, the Israeli
government had to come to us and say,
"Hey, listen. Let our people go, right?"
And quietly in in the aftermath of 911
where, you know, the country's on fire
and people are losing their minds, we
just let them all go. Um, so the
Israelis worked very hard to discredit
the story that there ever were any
dancing Israelis or that the Israelis
were spying on us or that the Israelis
had intelligence officers in New York
City the week of the 9/11 attacks. But
all of that was true. All of it. I said
at a conference uh recently too
um I believe that the Saudi government
was at least indirectly involved in the
9/11 attacks but I also believe that the
Israeli government had forewarning. The
Israelis are really really good at what
they do. They're very good spies. Mossad
is probably the best intelligence
service on the planet. Undoubtedly they
had penetrations of al-Qaeda. They knew
that attack was coming and they never
told us. And I want to know why.
>> With 911 too. And I'm going to segue to
the next topic because I think it's it's
important. As you mentioned, it was used
um to justify the war on terror. And we
know how that went. It was, you know,
even till now, many Americans still view
the Middle East as a whole, as a region,
through a terrorism lens based on what
happened on 911.
How much of that framing would you say
was constructed not not organically
through like you know this happened that
happened but intentionally after 911?
Oh, I think a lot of it was intentional
and I think a lot of it came directly
from from the Netanyahu government in
that Netanyahu saw 911 as the greatest
thing that ever happened for Israel
because and it wasn't just 911, it was
it was the u Iraqi uh invasion that came
a year later, a year and a half later in
that Netanyahu is a smart guy and he
knew he knew as soon as the first plane
hit the World Trade what the American
response was going to be. It was going
to be to go to the region and kill as
many Muslims as we possibly could kill.
Now, that wasn't the stated policy, of
course, but we all knew that that was
what was going to result. And so
Netanyahu
through his neocon friends like Richard
Pearl for example and Scooter Libby and
all these people that were surrounding
um Dick Cheney at the time, he knew that
the iron was hot and now it was the time
to strike and to put a little word in
the vice president's ear that the next
attack has to be against Iraq. There's
kind of a famous story that Richard
Pearl, who interestingly enough, never
became a Republican. He's still a
registered Democrat. That Richard Pearl
on the 12th of September went to the
White House to meet with these people,
all friends of his from when they were
in their 20s and all working for Senator
Scoop Jackson of Washington, also a
Democrat. On the 12th of September, he
went to the White House and said, "You
know, we have to attack Iraq, right?"
>> Like that was always the plan.
And so all they had to do was convince
Americans who, as I said earlier,
many of whom are very stupid people,
even though they think they're very
smart, convince them that Saddam Hussein
was somehow tied to al-Qaeda. Now, we
all knew that Osama bin Laden hated
Saddam Hussein as much as he hated the
United States. There's nothing Muslim
about Saddam Hussein. He he famously
made the Umrah, the minor pilgrimage in
the late 1980s with his vice president,
Isat Ibrahim,
and he didn't even know the prayers.
He didn't even know what the prayers
were. So Isat Ibrahim had to kneel just
behind him to whisper the prayers loudly
enough for Saddam to hear them and
repeat them. There was nothing Muslim
about him. But it was a convenient way
for the Israeli media and Netanyahu and
Apac and their friends in the Bush
administration to put this idea in the
vice president's ear that now's the time
to attack Iraq. And in the end, after 20
years, we killed more than two million
people in the region. Are we safer
because of it? I don't think so. Not in
the long term.
>> Absolutely. And uh you know one other I
think you just described something that
I want to ask you but you kind of did a
narrative autopsy there kind of going
through the different stages who
benefited what happened. If you were to
take aside from, you know, Iraq, one
major US storyline about the Middle East
from the last, let's say, 20 years and
do this narrative autopsy, basically how
it started, um, who fed it, who
amplified it, who benefited in the end,
what would you think or what would you
say would be the most revealing case?
>> I think the most obvious case, and it's
been discussed publicly, of course, but
the most obvious case is Dick Cheney.
Dick Cheney and the people in his
circle. uh they were really the very
definition of neoconservatism
in government. Everybody from from David
Addington and um Scooter Libby and Dubz
Zahheim and the people that they
installed at the Pentagon, they were all
true believers in a militarist and
activist foreign policy. And that
coincide coincided very nicely with
Netanyahu's idea of what American
foreign policy should be. So I I think
that the period from well 2000 but
really late 2001 to 2008 was one of the
most dangerous in modern American
history.
>> Obviously you've lived inside this
narrative machine that you're describing
right now. You've lived both both inside
and outside of it. So really witnessing
the manufacturing of a lot of these, you
know, narratives, but also being on this
side where you're also seeing it play
out, um, especially when it comes to how
the public interacts with all of this
information. What's one thing Americans
would, you know, understand differently
about the Middle East, um, and their own
government, you know, as as a player in
that, you know, game, if you will, if
they could see what you've seen in your
experience throughout all of this? Oh,
I'll tell you something that was revoly
to me.
And as background,
I studied the Middle East in college. I
have uh my my bachelor's degree is in
Middle Eastern studies. My my master's
degree was in legislative affairs, but
with a focus on foreign policy of the
Middle East. I speak Arabic. I lived in
the Middle East. I love the history. I
love the the literature, the poetry, the
food, the culture. I love all of it.
What was revvelatory to me was when we
started capturing al-Qaeda fighters, not
the leaders, but these kids 18, 19, 20
years old, they all essentially told the
same story or variations on the same
story. They were from some isolated
village in whatever country they came
from, Yemen, Tunisia, Saudi, whatever.
They were mostly illiterate.
They had no job skills.
They had very poor relationships with
their fathers, which struck me as very
interesting. And I'll let the
psychologists sort that out. I I don't
know what it means,
but they were of an age where they
wanted to get married.
And what father is going to want his
daughter to marry a kid who can't read,
can't write, can't work, and has no
prospects for the future? I wouldn't
want my daughter to marry a guy like
that,
>> right? And so the local imam went up to
them and said, "You know, why do you
want to stay in this village? You don't
want to stay in this village. You should
go to Afghanistan and make jihad against
the Americans and we'll pay you $300 a
month. And if you're martyed, we'll give
your parents a $500 martyrdom uh bonus."
And they said, "Okay,
have nothing better going on."
which led me to the conclusion that what
we really need to do in the Middle East
is spend money on economic development,
on education,
and on infrastructure. And it doesn't
have to be our money. It can be Emirati
money or guty money or Saudi money. But
what they really need is economic
development
so that people are busy building careers
and growing families rather than looking
for a place to go make jihad against the
Americans.
>> And you know what in response to that
John I think one thing that's
interesting I was actually interviewing
another you know guest on the topic of
Syria and you know you mentioned
economic development. The other aspect
to that conversation is even when the US
or even western countries, not just the
US, when they do propose that economic
development, it's it's always a Trojan
horse. It's it's never just hey, you
know, let's invest in the economic
development of this country. It's let's
let's do that, but obviously we want
something in return. Obviously, we want,
you know, a government that's either loy
either loyal to the west. uh we want you
know specific narratives being dominant
there and you know hey we'll even make
sure um they're institutionally
educationally as you mentioned spread
throughout the population. So even with
economic development and with Syria the
conversation was about the IMF now
getting involved um with you know the
fall of Assad and Galani power and all
these different foreign entities now
kind of getting ready to dive in. But we
we we know and I'm sure you know, you
know, you can explain and you know,
attest to it, economic development and
this idea of it being a Trojan horse.
How how true do you would you say that
is?
>> Totally true. I I've been to Yemen as an
example many many times. And every time
I go, it's worse than the previous time.
But I went on one trip. I think this was
probably my second or third trip. And I
met with
the Italian ambassador. No, I take that
back. It was the Italian defense
attaches and the Dutch ambassador.
And they were both very proud because
the European Union had just uh built a
new uh water, what do you call it, like
a sewage system, water treatment plant
for Sana.
And this was the first time that the
Yemenes were ever going to have portable
water. They were going to be able to
drink it right out of the tap and it was
so incredible and it was going to change
agriculture for the region and blah blah
blah.
And they would have been right
had the US not gotten involved along
with the Saudis to make sure that Ali
Abdalis
remained as the president. He was more
of a dictator than an elected leader um
of of Yemen. All the while the country
is falling around falling apart around
him. The south is trying to split off
again and make a new south Yemen. The
Houthies came out of the woodwork.
Nobody ever heard of Houthies until
whenever it was 2009 or 2008 or whatever
and the whole place ended up going to
hell. But you're right, one of the
problems that we run into in places like
that where economic development is
concerned is that there always is a quid
proquo and there shouldn't be. we should
do it because number one, it's the right
thing to do. But number two, if these
countries are able to develop their
economies,
they're not going to be sending refugees
to the United States. They're not going
to be sending young men into terrorist
training camps. They'll be able to take
care of themselves.
>> There's to me that there's no downside
to it to economic development and to
foreign aid. I'm a huge promoter of
foreign aid. I'm I'm part of a very
minuscule minority in the United States
on foreign aid, but I think that we
should, you know,
we should increase our foreign aid
budget by a hundfold
and implement these these uh programs,
>> right? And and kind of in closing, I
want your thoughts on something that I
know has become a huge
issue of public discourse in America,
and that is this whole America first
idea. this idea that, you know, hey, our
country and and it has come out
especially in relation to Israel but
also other countries.
>> Why are we spending so much on
furthering the interests of foreign
entities when we have so much to focus
on back home?
>> And this is kind of a conversation that
comes up very frequently. Do you think
though that it will ever get to a point
where America will truly be, you know,
America first, not looking to get
involved and extend its, you know,
imperial footprint?
>> No. It's like we can't help ourselves.
So on the one hand, this is one of those
rare areas where the progressive left
and the MAGA right intersect, right? And
they agree on this issue, at least as it
concerns military interventions. So
that's great. I think we should all be
working together
>> to stop American military interventions
uh overseas.
the two sides part company on the issue
of foreign aid and I think the MAGA is
wrong on foreign aid. I think for every
dollar we spend on foreign aid it's
going to save us $5 or $10 uh because we
we won't have like I said these refugee
problems or resettlement issues or civil
wars breaking out and attacks against
the United States. There was an attack
today in Syria that killed two American
soldiers and a and a Syrian translator.
Uh just as an example.
But with that said,
I don't think the the Republican party
is a MAGA uh America first party. I
think that it thinks it is and it's kind
of pretending to be, but I think that
the likes of Lindsey Graham at all just
can't wait until Donald Trump isn't
president anymore so they can be
in public neoons again. So, no, I don't
think it's going to change. Not over the
long term.
>> What about the likes of Marjorie Green?
I know she also, you know, is no longer
in government. So that could in fact be
proving the point of, you know, they
have no place in the government because
if you do try to go against that tide,
it'll really consume you. But do you
think the likes of this idea of
especially in relation to Israel, which
is what she was becoming very vocal on?
Do you think that is bound to increase
or will it just be shut down in the same
way each time?
>> Yeah, I think it'll be shut down. I was
very, very disappointed in Marjgery
Taylor Green for this resignation. In
fact, I had just said to a friend of
mine,"I can't believe that I get up
every day and agree with Marjorie Taylor
Green." Like, how did this happen?
Because I don't think I changed. I think
she changed. But um I remember thinking,
"Wow, this may actually begin to change
the national debate because she's even
though she was junior in the Republican
party, she was still very important in
the Republican party." Uh Nancy Mace is
another one. Nancy Mace is running for
governor, I think, of South Carolina.
She's in Congress now, but she's talking
about resigning
uh effective January 6th along with
Marjorie Taylor Green just to make a
political point that she doesn't like
the way things are being managed right
now. I think that's cowardly. I really
do. And the only reason Do you know why
they're they're hanging on until January
6th by any chance?
>> I I don't. because that's the day they
qualify for the pension.
>> Oh, okay. Interesting.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Shame on them both. So,
no. I I if there was going to be
if there was going to be a movement
within the Republican party that was
going to work to change the Republican
party on some of these issues, it could
have been led eventually by the likes of
Marjorie Taylor Green and Nancy Mace.
And now it won't be. I mean, Thomas
Massie can't do everything himself,
right? And Rand Paul is right on the
issues only half the time.
So, no, I I don't think we're going to
see any long-term changes.
>> So, you don't even think there's any
hope because I know, you know, one thing
we know at least American public opinion
has shifted dramatically on this
>> dramatically.
>> So, do you think that will ever
translate to, you know, changes on a
government level,
>> you know, if if we can enter into a
period of sustained peace,
it's possible, I suppose. Look at it
this way. After 911, George W. Bush's
approval ratings were at 90%.
And that lasted for about a year and
then it started to sink and sink
dramatically.
And then people finally realized we were
bogged down in forever wars. We weren't
going to get out of these wars. Not in a
year or two or or 10. It took us 20 to
get out of these wars. And so if we can
enter into a period of sustained peace,
it's going to make it a lot easier for
other people to flip on the issue and
say, "Yeah, you know what? We actually
don't need to be overseas. We don't need
to have a role in every conflict in the
world. Certainly, we have national
interests that we will need to protect,
obviously, but wars of choice are
completely different."
Well, John, thank you so much for
joining me on TMJ. Lovely to hear your
perspective, and I really do hope to
have you on again.
>> Thank you so much. I appreciate the
invitation.
>> If you like what you see here on TMJ
News, don't forget to like and share and
subscribe to our channel for more weekly
interviews. TMJ News is an independent
grassroots media outlet, and you can
find ways to support us by reading the
caption below. Thank you so much for
joining us on this episode, and I hope
you liked it.